{
    "response_code":0,
    "results":[
        {
            "question":"Which of the following statement is not correct about ICC?",
            "correct_answer":"ICC is also responsible for the staging of all ICC Events.",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "The ICC is the global governing body for cricket.",
                "ICC is also responsible for the staging of all ICC Events.",
                "The ICC also appoints all match officials that officiate at all sanctioned international matches.",
                "ICC has 53 members"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which countries are the latest full time members of the ICC? ",
            "correct_answer":"Afghanistan and Ireland",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Trinidad & Tobago and Burundi",
                "Afghanistan and Ireland",
                "Bangladesh and Nepal ",
                "None of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which of the following is the oldest test cricket playing country in the world?",
            "correct_answer":"Australia",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Australia",
                "India",
                "West Indies",
                "South Africa"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"  Where is the headquarter of the ICC?",
            "correct_answer":"Dubai",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                " London",
                "Sydney",
                "Cape town ",
                " Dubai"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" When was ICC established?",
            "correct_answer":"1909",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1960",
                "1953",
                "1909",
                "1877"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which of the following international competition is not organized by the ICC? ",
            "correct_answer":"Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Champions Trophy",
                "World Cricket League",
                "Under-19 Cricket World Cup",
                "Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy"
            ]
        },
        
        {
            "question":"Who is the current Chairman of the ICC? ",
            "correct_answer":"Shashank Manohar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "David Richardson",
                "Shashank Manohar",
                "Narayanaswami Srinivasan",
                "None of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Who is chosen at the ICC men's cricketer of the year 2017? ",
            "correct_answer":"Virat Kohli",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Steve Smith",
                "Virat Kohli",
                "K.L. Rahul",
                "Hasan Ali"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who of the following was the last President of the ICC?",
            "correct_answer":"Zaheer Abbas",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Mustafa Kamal",
                "Sharad Pawar",
                "Zaheer Abbas",
                "Alan Isaac"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"When was the first Cricket World Cup held? ",
            "correct_answer":"1975",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1928",
                "1975",
                "1953",
                "1979"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in first-class cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Brian Lara",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Brian Lara",
                " Don Bradman",
                "Lane Hutton",
                " Gary Sobers"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in ODI cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Rohit Sharma",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Chris Gayle",
                "Virender Sehwag",
                "Martin Guptill",
                "Rohit Sharma"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored most centuries in first-class cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Jack Hobbs",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Lane Hutton",
                "Jack Hobbs",
                "Wally Hammond"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored fastest century in ODI cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"AB de Villiers",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "AB de Villiers",
                "Shahid Afrid",
                "Vivian Richards",
                "Corey Anderson"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" ",
            "correct_answer":" ",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                " ",
                " ",
                " ",
                " "
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored fastest century in Test cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Brendon McCullum",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Misbah-ul-Haq",
                "Brendon McCullum",
                "Vivian Richards",
                "Adam Gilchrist"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored most runs in a Test match? ",
            "correct_answer":"Graham Gooch",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sunil Gavaskar",
                "Graham Gooch",
                "Brian Lara",
                "Don Bradman"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which cricketer had scored most runs in a Test series?",
            "correct_answer":"Don Bradman",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Kumar Sangakkara",
                "Don Bradman",
                "Hanif Mohammad",
                "Sunil Gavaskar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which cricketer had scored most test runs in a calendar year? ",
            "correct_answer":"Mohamed Yusuf",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "V. V. S. Laxman",
                "Rahul Dravid",
                "Mohamed Yusuf",
                "Steve Waugh"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which cricketer has taken most catches in ODI cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Mahela Jayawardene",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Ricky Ponting",
                "Jacques Kallis",
                "Mahela Jayawardene",
                "Mark Waugh"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":" Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in Test cricket? ",
            "correct_answer":"Brian Lara",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Brian Lara",
                "Matthew Hayden ",
                "Sanath Jayasuriya"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which is first Indian cricket tournament ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Bombay Triangular",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Pepsi Cup",
                " Bombay Series",
                "Bombay Triangular",
                "None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Indian played their First ODI Match against _______. ",
            "correct_answer":"England",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Pakistan",
                " England",
                "Australia",
                "South Africa"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Indian played their First T20 Match against _______. ",
            "correct_answer":"South Africa",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                " South Africa",
                "Pakistan",
                " England",
                "Australia "
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who was first test captain of Indian cricket team ? ",
            "correct_answer":"CK Nayudu",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Bapu Nadkarni",
                "Vijay Hazare",
                "Ajit Wadeka",
                "CK Nayudu"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"India won first ODI in ______ against _______. ",
            "correct_answer":"1975, East Africa",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1974, England",
                "None of these",
                "1975, East Africa",
                "1974, Pakistan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"India won first Test in ______ against _______ ",
            "correct_answer":"1951-52 , England",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1940-41 , England",
                "1950-51 , England",
                "1951-52 , England",
                "None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"India got First Test Series Victory in _______ against _________. ",
            "correct_answer":"1952,Pakistan",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1952 , Australia",
                "1952 , England",
                "1952,Pakistan",
                "None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"India got First Test Series Victory outside the Indian Subcontinent in _______ against _________. ",
                "correct_answer":"1967-68, New Zeland",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "1954-55 , England",
                "1967-68, New Zeland",
                " 1954-55 , Australia",
                "None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian bowler to take wicket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Mohammad Nissar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Bapu Nadkarni",
                "Imran Khan",
                "Mohammad Nissar",
                "Vyanktesh Prasad"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Cricketer to score a half century in test cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Amar Singh",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Lala Amarnath",
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Polly Umrigar",
                "Amar Singh"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian Cricketer to score a century in test cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Lala Amarnath",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Lala Amarnath",
                "Amar Singh",
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Polly Umrigar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Cricketer to score a double century in test cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Polly Umrigar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Lala Amarnath",
                "Amar Singh",
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Polly Umrigar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Cricketer to score a triple century in test cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Virendra Sehwag",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Virendra Sehwag",
                "Polly Umrigar",
                "Lala Amarnath",
                "Kapil Dev"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian to score century in ODI ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Kapil Dev",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Ajit Wadekar",
                "Kapil Dev",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Mohinder Amarnath"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian to score double century in ODI ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Sachin Tendulkar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Rohit Sharma",
                "Mahendra Singh Dhoni",
                "Ravindra Jadeja",
                "Sachin Tendulkar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who recorded first hat-trick in Test Match ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Harbhajan Singh",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Bapu Nadkarni",
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Harbhajan Singh",
                "Kapil Dev"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian bowler to record hat-trick in ODI Match ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Chetan Sharma",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Bapu Nadkarni",
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Harbhajan Singh",
                "Kapil Dev"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"India Won first cricket world cup championship in year _________. ",
            "correct_answer":"1983",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "2011",
                "1979",
                "1987",
                "1983"
            ]
        },

        {
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian Batsman to complete 10,000 runs in Test Cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Sunil Gavaskar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Ajit Wadekar",
                "Ravi Shastri",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Sunil Gavaskar"
            ]
        },{
            "question":"Which of the following is first Indian Batsman to complete 10,000 runs in ODI Cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Sachin Tendulkar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Ajit Wadekar",
                "Ravi Shastri",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Sunil Gavaskar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is first Indian Cricketer to score 100 centuries in Tests and ODIs combined ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Sachin Tendulkar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Ricky Ponting",
                "Sunil Gawaskar",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "None of these "
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is first Indian Bowler to take all 10 wickets in an innings ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Anil Kumble",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Anil Kumble",
                "Kapil Dev",
                "Bapu Nakarni "
            ]
        },

        {
            "question":"Who is First Indian Batsman to score 50 centuries in Test Cricket ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Sachin Tendulkar",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sunil Gavaskar",
                "Saurav Ganguli",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Rahul Dravid "
            ]
        },{
            "question":"Who is First Indian Batsman to score two centuries in same test match ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Vijay Hazare",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sunil Gavaskar ",
                "Saurav Ganguli",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Vijay Hazare"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is First Indian Batsman to score two duck in same test match ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Vijay Hazare",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sunil Gavaskar",
                "Saurav Ganguli",
                "Sachin Tendulkar",
                "Vijay Hazare"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is First Indian Batsman to score 1000 runs in test ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Vijay Hajare",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Sunil Gavaskar",
                "Saurav Ganguli",
                "Ravi Shastri ",
                "Vijay Hajare"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is First Indian player to score a century in three successive Test matches ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Vijay Hazare",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Saurav Ganguly",
                "Bapu Nadkarni",
                "Vijay Hazare",
                "Lala Amarnath"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question":"Who is first Indian cricketer to score 4000 runs and take 400 wickets ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Kapil Dev",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "Chetan Sharma",
                "Harbhajan Singh",
                "Anil Kumble",
                "Kapil Dev"
            ]
        },

        {
            "question":"Which is first Indian bowler to take wicket on the first bowl of carrier in Test Match ? ",
            "correct_answer":"Nilesh Kulkarni",
            "incorrect_answers":[
                "R Ashwin",
                "Ramesh Powar",
                "Nilesh Kulkarni",
                "Vyankatesh Prasad"
            ]
        }
        




    ]
}
